VIVEK BHARDWAJ

Phone: +91-8510032727 Father's Name: Mr. Rajiv Kumar Sharma

Email: vivekbhardwaj2426@gmail.com

Birth Date:

July 26, 1993

Marital Status: Single

Languages: Hindi and English

PROFILE

Professional with exposure in Channel Sales, Sales Process and Quality, Customer Experience, Digital Marketing through Social Media, Retail finance, Channel Finance, Advertising, Manpower Development and Business break-even analysis. Management professional with Master of Business Administration focused in International Business and Marketing from Faculty of Management Studies, Banaras Hindu University. Currently pursuing Financial Analyst certification course.

EDUCATION

Currently Pursuing Currently Pursuing

Certification – Social Media Marketing | Indian Institute of Digital Education February 2019

Masters, Business Administration | Faculty of Management Studies, Banaras Hindu University May 2017

Computer Science Engineering | Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam Technical University June 2014

Senior School Certification | The Army Public School March 2010

High School Certification | The Army Public School March 2008

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2017 - Currently Working

Area Manager | Mahindra & Mahindra Ltd. | June 2017 - Current

Responsibilities:

- Consulting channel partners to grow business and profitability by identifying opportunities and gaps for positive impact.
- Responsible for end to end operations of dealerships in multiple districts.
- Analysis of market data and preparing strategies to counter competition.
- Targeted sales achievement and market share improvement in assigned regions.
- Planning and executing ATL campaigns in Newspaper Ads, Radio Campaigns, Digital Media for brand building.
- Planning and executing BTL promotional campaigns for creating robust sales funnel.
- Sales forecasting, market trend analysis and competition tracking to ensure timely strategy development.
- Mapping of territories segment wise, application wise and potential wise for specific products.
- Analyzing manpower requirement and ensuring adequacy and productivity in assigned regions.
- Identifying & deal with strategic customers and develop sustainable relationship with them.
- Working with banks and NBFCs to design and execute retail finance schemes as per customer requirements.
- Fund Management and Channel finance for channel partners in assigned regions.
- Interface between brand team and end customers for market intelligence.
- Capability building of dealer General Managers, Sales Managers, Product Managers and Sales Consultants regarding product, competition, finance, customer need analysis.

Special Projects:

- Developing robust virtual numbers enquiry management system.
- Digital Marketing Developing and handling Facebook page Mahindra Automotive Gujarat https://www.facebook.com/MahindraAutomotiveGujrat/
- Showroom Breakeven Analysis to ensure channel profitability.
- Market Share reports development for Gujarat.

Professional Achievements:

- Assigned as Area Manager within 7 months before completion of one-year training period.
- Assigned as Area Manager for dealership with highest stake at Gujarat level Punjab Automobiles.
- Planned and executed strategy to take Gujarat area office from last area office to number one area office across India in Enquiry Management Process through Virtual Numbers.
- Learned and implemented process for digital lead generation at regional level. Recognized at national level.
- Market Share improvement of 7% across assigned regions.

May 2016 - July 2016

Marketing Intern | Advertising and Marketing - Nexa Channel | Maruti Suzuki India Ltd.

Project: Marketing strategy to use celebrity endorsement as a marketing communication tool in MSIL. May 2016 – July 2016

· Ranveer Singh's compatibility and fitness check for brand endorsement of Maruti Suzuki's sedan 'Ciaz'.

Mentor: Mr. Gaurav Aggarwal, Brand Manager - Ciaz

December 2015 - January 2016

Banking Intern | Agri-Loans | Kotak Mahindra Bank Ltd.

Project: Analysis of fund based working capital limits offered by KMBL and other banks

- Understanding of working capital limits required by Agri-based firms
- Understanding of banking operations

Mentor: Mr. Abhishek Jain - Regional Manager - Agri Loans

January 2014 - July 2014

Ad-Operation Executive | Exponential Inc.

Responsibilities: Trafficking and configuring exponential client campaigns. Reviewing and approving advertiser's creative materials.

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Adaptable and Team Player
- Communication and Presentation Skills
- Problem Solving and fixing
- Discipline and Integrity

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Athletics Marathon
- Outdoor Sports

- Studying strategic and geo-politics issues
- Motivation and Capability building

Declaration

I, Vivek Bhardwaj, hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Vivek Bhardwaj

Place: Ahmedabad